When the game ends, the mystery begins.
Glass Onion: A Knives Out Mystery is a comedy, crime,
mystery film directed by Rian Johnson.
World-famous detective Benoit Blanc heads to Greece to peel back the layers of a
mystery surrounding a tech billionaire and his eclectic crew of friends.
Benoit Blanc, played by Daniel Craig.
Miles Bron, played by Edward Norton.
Andi Brand, played by Janelle Monáe.
Claire Debella, played by Kathryn Hahn.
Lionel Toussaint, played by Leslie Odom Jr..
Birdie Jay, played by Kate Hudson.
Glass Onion: A Knives Out Mystery is a 2022 American mystery film written and
directed by Rian Johnson, and produced by Johnson and Ram Bergman.
It is a standalone sequel to the 2019 film Knives Out, and the
second installment in the Knives Out film series.
Glass Onion sees Daniel Craig return as master detective Benoit Blanc as he takes on a new case
revolving around tech billionaire Miles Bron (played by Edward Norton) and his closest friends.
The ensemble cast also includes Janelle Monáe, Kathryn Hahn, Leslie Odom Jr.,
Jessica Henwick, Madelyn Cline, Kate Hudson, and Dave Bautista.
Johnson had considered several films featuring the Benoit
Blanc character before the first film's release.
A sequel was greenlit by its original distributor Lionsgate in 2020, but in March 2021
Netflix bought the rights to two Knives Out sequels for $469 million.
The cast signed on that May.
Filming took place on the Greek island of Spetses in June and July
2021, and continued in Belgrade until September.
Following its world premiere at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 10, 2022, Glass Onion
began a one-week limited theatrical release on November 23, 2022, and grossed $15 million.
Netflix began streaming it on December 23.
Like its predecessor, Glass Onion received critical acclaim, with reviewers praising Johnson's screenplay and direction,
the performances of the cast, and the musical score; although some viewed it as inferior to the first film.
The National Board of Review named Glass Onion as
one of the top ten films of 2022.
The film received a nomination for Best Adapted Screenplay at the 95th
Academy Awards, and received numerous other accolades.
A third Knives Out film, Wake Up Dead Man, was
released in theaters on November 26, 2025.
The film explores themes of detective, greece,
investigation, mona lisa (la gioconda), dark comedy.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and mind_bending.